A gaze into the abyss of the human soul.
Into the Abyss is a documentary, crime film directed by Werner Herzog.
We do not know when and how we will die.
Death Row inmates do.
Werner Herzog embarks on a dialogue with Death Row inmates, asks questions about life and
death and looks deep into these individuals, their stories, their crimes.
Narrator (voice), played by Werner Herzog.
Self - Convicted Murderer, played by Jason Burkett.
Self - Death House Chaplin (as The Reverend Richard
Lopez), played by Richard Lopez.
Self - Montgomery County Sheriff's Department, played by Damon Hall.
Self - Daughter and Sister to Victims, played by Lisa Stolter-Balloun.
Self - Older Brother of Jeremy, played by Charles Richardson.
Into the Abyss (subtitled A Tale of Death, a Tale of Life) is a 2011
documentary film written and directed by Werner Herzog.
It is about capital punishment, and focuses on a triple homicide
that occurred in Montgomery County, Texas, in 2001.
In the film, Herzog interviews the two young men convicted of the crime, Michael Perry (who received a death sentence) and Jason Burkett (who was given a life
sentence), as well as family members and acquaintances of the victims and criminals, and individuals who have taken part in executions in Texas.
The primary focus of the film is not the details of the case or the question of Michael and Jason's guilt or innocence, and,
although Herzog's voice can be heard as he conducts the interviews, there is a minimal amount of narration.
He never appears onscreen, unlike in many of his films.
The film was first screened on September 3, 2011, at the Telluride Film Festival, and had its
official world premiere on September 8 at the Toronto International Film Festival.
After strong festival showings and a surge of interest in the issue of capital punishment in the United States, Herzog
requested that the film be rushed into general theatrical release, which occurred on November 11, 2011.
The film explores themes of death penalty, texas, death
row, capital punishment, death row inmate.
The tone is thought_provoking.